Guide to the Sarita Daftary-Steel collection of East New York oral histories 2015.011
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Yeancades, Carmen, 2014 August 8; 2015.011.120
  Carmen Yeancades was born in 1950 in Malta and immigrated to Manhattan, New York, with her family when she was one year old. Her family moved to the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn to live with extended family in 1955 upon the death of her mother. They lived in East New York until 1962, and eventually moved to Richmond Hill, Queens. Carmen attended Queens College and has worked with Estee Lauder for many years. She currently lives in Bardonia, New York.
  In the interview, Carmen Yeancades speaks in detail about her life as a child in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn. She describes the dissolution of the neighborhood, blockbusting, the influx of many Southern Black families, the exodus of Jewish families, White flight, and the reconstruction of the neighborhood in preparation for new housing projects. The interview was conducted by Sarita Daftary-Steel at Yeancades' home in Bardonia, New York.
  African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Catholic schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Community organizing |z New York (State) |z Kings County; East New York (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions; Education -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country; Housing |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Jews |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Public schools |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Race relations |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Real estate business -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Social classes |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Linden Houses (Housing complex); New York City Housing Authority; Yeancades, Carmen